Julian Ehiem

Active Secret Clearance jules.ehiem@gmail.com | 240-354-3436 | Manassas, VA

github.com/julianehiem | julianehiem.dev | linkedin.com/in/julianehiem

CAREER PROFILE

Front End Web Developer with an Active Secret Clearance, that implements Information Technology solutions and tools for clients and companies in government contracting, cybersecurity and defense sectors. Extensive experience working with team sizes from 5-25 people.

Core competencies include HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6, React, Redux, Bootstrap, SASS, Git. Familiarity with Node.js, Rest APIs, VScode, Bash scripting and design tools like Adobe XD and Photoshop. Foundational knowledge of User Experience Design Principles, Version control, Functional programming and Object-oriented Programming.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

COVID TRACKER | WEBSITE, GITHUB

Fall 2020

- Built React/Redux application for visualizing Covid-19 data
- Implemented Material UI, Chart.js library and CountUp.js.

WEATHERHUB | WEBSITE, GITHUB

Fall 2020

- Built React/Redux Progressive weather application.
- Implemented Open Weather API.

HELIOS GYM | WEBSITE, GITHUB

Summer 2020

- Built a simple website using Bootstrap.
- Implemented CSS Grid and Flexbox.

EDUCATION

FREECODECAMP and LINKEDIN LEARNING

2019-2020

2014-2018

Online Software Dev. Program

CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA

Bachelor of Art in Philosophy

WORK EXPERIENCE

U.S. STATE DEPARTMENT SPECIAL ISSUANCE AGENCY

CONTRACT VISA SPECIALIST | Washington, DC

Jan 2021 - Present

- Liaise with government and embassy officials to ensure timely travel
- Achieved the Consular Affairs Leadership Award for modelling teamwork and Integrity

CONTRACT SUPPORT ASSOCIATE II | Washington, DC

July 2020 - Dec 2020

- Successfully trained and onboarded 3 trainees into the SIA processing team
- Marginally increased consistency and quality of work output while increasing productivity by 6%

FREELANCE August 2020

FRONT END DEVELOPER/ DESIGNER | Manassas, VA

- Designed wireframes and mockups of website and app
- Created a simple prototype using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.